Shivam Bajaj

PRODUCT MANAGER

Details

Bengaluru

India

+919034442879

sbajaj040@gmail.com

Skills

Agile Methodologies

Google Analytics

Product Management

SQL

JIRA

Leadership

Project Management

Data Analysis

SDLC

Python Django

Figma

HTML5

CSS

JS

Links

<u>Linkedin</u>

<u>Portfolio</u>

Profile

Skilled and experienced Product Manager with experience in product marketing, product introduction, and the overall management of a product life from conception to fruition.

"An analytical thinker who works collaboratively to get the job done."

Work Experience

Product Manager, Infilect Technologies, Bengaluru

AUGUST 2022 - PRESENT

- Led the life cycle of InfiViz Shots for real-time audits, resulting in a 20% increase in user satisfaction and a 15% increase in revenue.
- Migrated Analytics from Tableau to Power BI, achieving 70% faster loading times and in less than 20% of the cost for Tableau.
- Integrated ELK and Mix Panel to streamline issue resolution, reducing resolution time by 30%...
- Revamped photo-taking UX, achieving a 25% increase in user engagement and a 20% reduction in task completion time.
- Utilized on-device AI & implemented ML and computer vision technologies with real-time insights and achieving a 30% reduction in processing time.
- Galvanized cross-functional teams to deploy versatile reporting dashboards contributing to a 40% boost in revenue generation.
- Led iOS and Android SDK development, ensuring seamless integration with clients' tech stacks. Resulted in increased product adoption by 40%.

Product Manager, BlueStacks Inc. (Now.gg), Gurgaon

MARCH 2021 - AUGUST 2022

- Led development of Cloud Gaming Platform (Now.gg), achieving 10% revenue growth.
- Spearheaded Scrum calls and cross-functional teams, fostering a collaborative and high-performing culture while increasing team productivity by 25% and delivered projects 20% ahead of schedule.
- Introduced Multi-Instance Manager in BlueStacks 5, driving 3.5% increase in DAU.
- Worked on the Advanced Controls Editor resulting in increase in the User Engagement by 15%.
- Collaborated with Design team to improve the User Experience, improving user adoption by 20%.
- Conceptualized game economy, resulting in 10% revenue boost.
- Constantly researched support tickets and analyzing the data in order to find issues beforehand, increasing stickiness by 6%.
- Developed Chatbot, reducing support response time by 30%.

Associate Product Consultant, Dell Technologies, Gurgaon

JUNE 2019 - MARCH 2021

- Orchestrated Sales App migration from CLI-based tool to Dell Sales Application, reducing order processing time by 25%.
- Led CRM tool development and Migration to Salesforce, increasing sales productivity by 20%.
- Enhanced Global Order Visibility, boosting user satisfaction by 30% and sales by 15%.

- Automated quotation creation, saving 50% time and improving accuracy by 40%.
- Provided technical guidance, ensuring successful delivery of the products and client satisfaction.

Senior Support Engineer, Dell Technologies, Gurgaon

MARCH 2023 - JUNE 2019

- Designed and developed REST APIs using Python and Django frameworks resulting 5% reduction in response time.
- Analyzed performance data and identified areas for optimization while improving stability with minimal downtime.
- Collaborated with developers and product teams to resolve customer issues quickly and efficiently

Education

Bachelor of Technology, Kurukshetra University, Kurukshetra

AUGUST 2013 - JUNE 2017

Courses

Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO), UpGrad

AUGUST 2021

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, EMC

AUGUST 2020